Akian
아 키안
i have everything
나는 모든 것을 가지고 있다
If you want
네가 원한다면
I am here
나는 여기 있다
this hand
이 손
Can I hold on?
내가 붙잡을 수 있을까?
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
Go quickly and meet Huawei Wei.
빨리 가서 화웨이웨이를 만나보세요.
He lost a lot of blood.
그 사람 피를 많이 흘렸어요
Please speak carefully. What happened to Hua Rongzhou?
조심스럽게 말해 보세요. Hua Rongzhou에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Hurry up and meet me, madam.
빨리 가서 만나보세요 부인
Teacher, thank you so much for today.
선생님, 오늘도 정말 감사드립니다
Come see us off and leave your books.
배웅하러 오셔서 책을 맡기시고
I just pretended I didn't hear anything else.
그냥 다른 건 못 들은 척 했어요.
I don't think I need to mention it again in the future.
앞으로는 다시 언급할 필요가 없을 것 같아요
walk
걷다
House owner
집주인
you talk about me
당신은 나에 대해 이야기
I've been waiting for this for so long
난 이걸 너무 오랫동안 기다려왔어
Why are you so anxious now?
지금 왜 이렇게 불안해?
like a little boy
어린 소년처럼
Doctor, how is Huarongzhou?
박사님, 화룽저우는 어떤가요?
Go back to your wife, people at home are fine.
아내에게 돌아가라 집 사람들은 괜찮다
It's just that the wound broke down a second time.
그냥 상처가 두 번째로 무너졌을 뿐이야
Thank you for your hard work
고생많았어
I'm taking medicine now
지금 약을 먹고 있어요
I'm already asleep
벌써 잠들었어
Second crack?
두 번째 균열?
- Qian Zhi - Yes, honey.
- Qian Zhi - 응, 얘야.
what's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Don't you know, madam?
모르시나요, 부인?
Back to the girl's story, guard Hua was injured as the sun was setting over the cliffs.
소녀 이야기로 돌아가서, 경비병 Hua는 해가 절벽 위로 질 때 부상을 입었습니다.
Maybe it was because I got slapped by my uncle again yesterday.
어쩌면 어제 또 삼촌한테 뺨을 맞았기 때문이었는지도 모른다.
Only then did the wound open again
그제서야 상처가 다시 ​​터졌다
Fall off a cliff?
절벽에서 떨어지나요?
That Lihua escort followed that girl.
그 리화 에스코트가 그 소녀를 따라갔어
fall into a valley together
함께 계곡에 빠지다
He did not return with her until the next morning.
그는 다음날 아침까지 그 여자와 함께 돌아오지 않았다
We saw a wound on his back
우리는 그의 허리에 상처를 보았습니다
Probably when I fell
아마 떨어졌을 때였을 거야
I accidentally got scratched by a tree branch.
실수로 나뭇가지에 긁혔습니다.
He didn't say much to us either.
그 사람도 우리한테는 별로 말 안 했어
Would you like to follow me down the valley?
나를 따라 계곡 아래로 내려가볼까?
Muyao, you owe me
무야오, 나한테 빚진 거야
-Lady - Aquian‥
-레이디 - 아퀴안‥
Why didn't you tell me?
왜 나에게 말하지 않았나요?
He was injured?
그 사람이 부상을 입었다고?
Madam, these days, because
부인 요즘은 왜냐면
Feeling depressed and silent all day
하루종일 우울하고 말이 없다
I can't hear a word anyone else says.
다른 사람이 하는 말은 한 마디도 듣지 못해요
After all, it's just a nursing home.
결국, 그것은 단지 요양원일 뿐입니다.
He didn't even listen to his own advice
그는 자신의 조언도 듣지 않았다
How dare we say anything at this point?
이 시점에서 우리가 어떻게 감히 무슨 말을 할 수 있겠습니까?
Guard Hua insisted on guarding the courtyard despite being wounded.
경비병 Hua는 부상을 입었음에도 불구하고 안뜰을 지키겠다고 고집했습니다.
Yesterday I got slapped by my uncle again.
어제 또 삼촌한테 뺨을 맞았어
The person was like this without saying a word.
그 사람은 한 마디 말도 없이 이러고 있었어
Until he couldn't take it anymore and passed out in front of me.
그 사람이 더 이상 참지 못하고 내 앞에서 기절할 때까지
Only then did I realize how badly he was hurt.
그제서야 나는 그가 얼마나 심하게 다쳤는지 깨달았습니다.
- But the eldest lady doesn't care at all - Cuizhu
- 하지만 큰 아줌마는 전혀 신경 쓰지 않는다 - Cuizhu
-Fahrenheit protects him‥ -Woman
-화씨가 그를 보호한다 ‥ -여자
The doctor just prescribed some medication and told me to take it later.
의사는 방금 약을 처방하고 나중에 먹으라고 했습니다.
Let's go down and take a look first.
먼저 내려가서 살펴보자
I told you before that I like ignoring you.
아까도 말했잖아 난 널 무시하는 걸 좋아한다고
I'm not sure yet
아직 확신이 안 섰어요
Now it seems
이제는 것 같다
You all care deeply about me.
너희 모두는 나에게 깊은 관심을 갖고 있다
But I'm always selfish and only think about myself
하지만 난 항상 이기적이고 내 자신만 생각하는 편이야
This applies to you
이것은 당신에게 해당됩니다
Same goes for my brother.
내 동생도 마찬가지야
decent
괜찮은
It's not too late this time, I found it
이번에야말로 늦지 않았어 발견했어
What kind of dream was this?
이건 무슨 꿈을 꾸던 걸까?
I hold on too tightly and won't let go
너무 꽉 붙잡고 놓지 않아
Do you wake up and your wound still hurts?
일어났는데 아직도 상처가 아프나요?
Can you let go now?
이제 놓아줄 수 있나요?
What I said just now isn't over
지금 내가 한 말도 끝나지 않았어
I was dragged here because of you
난 너 때문에 여기로 끌려갔어
This subordinate deserves to die.
이 부하직원은 죽어 마땅하다
Please punish my master.
주인님을 처벌해주세요
What crimes deserve death?
어떤 범죄가 죽어야 마땅합니까?
You are seriously injured.
당신은 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
It's a good idea to go back to bed and get some rest.
다시 잠자리에 들고 휴식을 취하는 것이 좋습니다.
wake up quickly
빨리 일어나
You put the clothes on first.
네가 먼저 옷을 입혀라.
See you later
나중에 봐요
I didn't sleep well last night
어젯밤에 잠을 잘 못 잤어요
I want to squint a little more.
좀 더 눈을 가늘게 뜨고 싶다
If anything happens, call me back.
무슨 일 있으면 다시 전화해
Last night I was guarding the yard gate
어젯밤에 나는 마당 문을 지키고 있었다
Honey, are you in the Chinese escort room?
얘야, 중국 호위실에 있니?
He is sleepy and I can't wake him up.
그는 졸려서 깨울 수 없다
stayed a little longer
조금 더 머물렀어요
Don't worry, lady. Luckily, I thought about it last night.
걱정하지 마세요, 아가씨 다행스럽게도 어젯밤에 그것에 대해 생각했습니다.
It seems the girl has gone back to bed.
그 소녀가 다시 잠자리에 든 것 같습니다.
Other people fooled me like this
남들은 이렇게 속였구나
What do I care about?
나는 무엇을 걱정합니까?
Differences Between Men and Women
남성과 여성의 차이점
Besides, he is still master and servant.
게다가 그는 여전히 주인이자 종이다.
Girl, you better be more careful
Girl 좀 더 조심하는 게 좋을 거야
If this spreads widely
이게 널리 퍼지면
I am afraid of losing my identity.
정체성을 잃을까 두렵습니다.
I know what people say is scary
사람 말이 무서운 거 알아
But because of me, Huarongzhou was seriously injured.
하지만 나 때문에 화룽저우가 심각한 부상을 입었다.
Even if you serve tea and water in his room
그 사람 방에 차와 물을 대접해도
Also appropriate
또한 적절하다
if it were you
만약 당신이었다면
I'll be the same too
나도 똑같을 거야
Now for me
이제 나에게는
For a long time you were no longer servants.
오래 전부터 너희는 더 이상 하인이 아니니라
So please don't say things like that from now on.
그러니까 앞으로는 그런 말 하지 마세요.
Probably around this time
아마 이때쯤이면
in this place
이 장소에서
None of this is appropriate
이 중 어느 것도 적절하지 않습니다
But I still want to ask if you are willing.
하지만 그래도 당신이 의향이 있는지 묻고 싶습니다.
If you have my other half in your heart
네 마음속에 나의 반쪽이 있다면
Leave everything else to me
다른 건 다 나한테 맡겨
I will make you fair and good
나는 너를 공정하고 훌륭하게 만들 것이다
stand next to me
내 옆에 서서
Akian
아 키안
i have everything
나는 모든 것을 가지고 있다
If you want
네가 원한다면
I am here
나는 여기 있다
The girl just went to bed. What do you want?
그 소녀는 방금 잠자리에 들었는데 무엇을 원하세요?
If it's not urgent, let's talk later.
급하지 않다면 나중에 이야기하자.
kneel down and punish
무릎을 꿇고 벌을 내린다
There's no need to give the girl an alarm
여자한테 알람을 줄 필요는 없어
Why are you kneeling here?
왜 여기에 무릎을 꿇고 있습니까?
The medicine is ready
약이 준비되었습니다
- What are you going to do? - Please get out of the way. I have a favor to ask you, Madam.
- 무엇을 할 건가요? - 비켜주세요. 마님에게 부탁할 게 있습니다.
No, she's still sleeping
아니요, 그 여자는 아직도 자고 있어요
-You can't go in. -Please get out of the way.
-들어갈 수 없습니다. -비켜주세요.
- Tsuiju ‥ You cannot enter - Madam ‥
- 추이주 ‥ 들어가실 수 없습니다 - 부인 ‥
- I have a question, ma'am. - You can't go in, Kuiju.
- 여쭤볼 게 있어요, 부인 - 들어가시면 안 돼요, 쿠이주.
－Big Lady ‥ －Qian Ji ‥
－빅 레이디 ‥ －치안 지 ‥
What's going on outside?
밖에서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
- I have a question to ask - Cuizhu, I told you.
- 물어볼 게 있어요 - Cuizhu, 내가 말했잖아요
-You let go . -You really can’t go in, she’s still sleeping.
-너 놔 -너 진짜 못 들어가, 여자 아직 자고 있어
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Yesterday, Guard Hua was seriously injured and lost consciousness.
어제 경비병 Hua는 심각한 부상을 입고 의식을 잃었습니다.
okay…
그렇군요…
For loyalty to protect the Lord,
주님을 지키기 위한 충성을 위해,
Just don't punish the person.
그냥 그 사람을 처벌하지 마세요
When did I punish him?
내가 언제 그 사람을 처벌했습니까?
Guard Hua is now kneeling outside.
경비병 Hua가 지금 밖에 무릎을 꿇고 있습니다.
Qianzhi, help me comb my hair.
Qianzhi, 머리 빗는 걸 도와줘
Cuizhu, please bring Hua Rongzhou later.
Cuizhu, 나중에 Hua Rongzhou를 데려와주세요
yes
예
There's no need to kneel
무릎을 꿇을 필요는 없어
The injury didn't heal
부상은 낫지 않았어
Why don't you just lie down?
그냥 누워 있는 게 어때요?
-Who punished you? -Her subordinate got angry with the girl.
-누가 당신을 처벌 했습니까? -부하가 그 소녀에게 화를 냈습니다.
deserve to be punished
처벌받아 마땅하다
Why are you so honest?
왜 그렇게 솔직해요?
I told you I was nothing
난 아무것도 아니라고 말했잖아
i was thinking
나는 생각하고 있었다
Take a break and ask again
잠시 쉬었다가 다시 물어보세요
I think it would be better to forget about it now.
이제는 잊어버리는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Please save me the trouble of thinking alone.
혼자 생각하는 수고를 덜어주세요
Please go down first. I have something to ask that person.
먼저 내려가세요 그 사람한테 물어볼 게 있어요
i ask you
나는 당신에게 묻습니다
You found me so quickly that day in the valley
그 날 계곡에서 넌 나를 너무 빨리 찾았어
Did you jump with me?
나랑 같이 뛰어내렸어?
yes
예
What about back injuries?
허리 부상은 어떻습니까?
Did you get scratched when you fell?
넘어졌을 때 긁혔나요?
no
아니요
After my men landed on the river,
내 부하들이 강에서 상륙한 후,
Traces of a man dressed in black were found.
검은옷을 입은 남자의 흔적이 발견됐다
I thought about it
나는 생각했다
That's the man in black who jumped with him.
그 사람은 그와 함께 뛰어내린 검은 옷을 입은 남자야
I'll attack first
내가 먼저 공격할게
I was injured while fighting him.
그와 싸우다가 부상을 입었다.
etc.
등.
If the fight continues
싸움이 계속된다면
I am afraid that it will become more difficult to find the person you are looking for.
당신이 찾고 있는 사람을 찾는 것이 더욱 어려워질까 두렵습니다.
Have you seen his face?
그 사람 얼굴 본 적 있어요?
he covered his face
그는 얼굴을 가렸다
maybe i misunderstood
어쩌면 내가 오해했을지도 몰라
This man in black doesn't want to fight me at all
이 검은 옷을 입은 남자는 나랑 전혀 싸우고 싶어하지 않아요
So after both sides suffered losses,
그래서 양측 모두 손실을 입은 후,
he left in a hurry
그는 서둘러 떠났다
I couldn't catch up either.
나도 따라잡지 못했다
I'm sorry I don't think you misunderstood.
당신이 오해한 것은 아닐 것 같아 유감입니다.
Jumped off a cliff and got hurt
절벽에서 뛰어내려 다쳐
Why don't you tell me these things?
이런 것들을 나에게 말해 보는 게 어때?
Because the girl didn't ask
그 소녀는 묻지 않았기 때문에
I've been so depressed these days
요즘 너무 우울했어요
But what will happen to you next?
하지만 앞으로 당신에게 무슨 일이 일어날까요?
You should take the initiative and tell me.
네가 솔선해서 나한테 말해야 해.
Did you understand?
이해했나요?
I am always busy with my work.
나는 항상 내 일로 바쁘다.
Too many aspects cannot be covered
너무 많은 측면을 다룰 수 없음
I know you usually talk less
나는 당신이 평소에 말을 덜 하는 걸 알아요
But you've done so much for me
하지만 당신은 나에게 너무 많은 일을 해줬어요
I need to learn how to speak positively to myself.
나에게 적극적으로 말하는 법을 배워야 한다
I have never seen you as a servant
나는 당신을 하인으로 본 적이 없습니다
So, you can talk freely.
그러니까 자유롭게 얘기해도 돼.
I don't think you're trying to show off.
내 생각엔 당신이 과시하려고 하는 게 아닌 것 같아
i know
알아요
Also, if you are injured, you need to take good care of yourself.
또한, 부상을 입었다면, 자신을 잘 돌봐야 합니다.
Don’t force yourself to accept Zhong Yeran’s cheek when he tries to cause trouble.
문제를 일으키려는 종예란의 뺨을 억지로 받아들이지 마십시오.
Before protecting others
남을 보호하기 전에
First you need to learn how to protect yourself
먼저 자신을 보호하는 법을 배워야 합니다
Did you understand?
이해했나요?
That girl once said this to me.
그 소녀가 나에게 이런 말을 한 적이 있다.
But I've thought about it privately for a long time.
하지만 나는 그것에 대해 오랫동안 개인적으로 생각했습니다.
To me, a woman...
나한테 여자는 ‥
Our people are so nice
우리 사람들은 참 착해요
I don't care what happens to me
나에게 무슨 일이 일어나든 상관없어
I just don't want to see that girl suffer any injustice.
나는 단지 그 소녀가 어떤 불의로 고통받는 것을 보고 싶지 않을 뿐입니다.
all right
알겠어요
You quickly go back and lie down.
너는 빨리 돌아가서 누워라.
Guarding the yard is not necessary these days.
요즘에는 마당을 지키는 것이 필요하지 않습니다.
good luck
행운을 빕니다
If you need anything, please contact Qian Zhi.
필요한 것이 있으면 Qian Zhi에게 문의하세요.
yes
예
correct
옳은
I have poor eyesight.
시력이 좋지 않아요
From now on, I should wear less black clothes.
이제부터 검은색 옷은 덜 입어야지
Otherwise I wouldn't have even known you were hurt.
그렇지 않으면 당신이 다친 줄도 몰랐을 거예요.
good
좋은
Will you choose or not?
당신은 선택할 것인가, 말 것인가?
If you don't choose one of the two
둘 중 하나를 선택하지 않으면
I don't want either.
둘 중 어느 것도 원하지 않습니다.
This way you don't have to worry.
이렇게 하면 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
Feeling guilty for only saving one person
한 사람만 구했다는 죄책감
Muyao, you owe me
무야오, 나한테 빚진 거야
-Lady - Aquian‥
-레이디 - 아퀴안‥
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
uncle
삼촌
Middle selection up and down
중택 상하
Go immediately and do your best to find the whereabouts of the big lady.
즉시 가서 온 힘을 다해 큰 부인의 행방을 찾아보세요.
yes
예
walk
걷다
Yesterday I went to Huashen's funeral.
어제 나는 Huashen의 장례식에 갔다.
News of breakup with Hua Qian
Hua Qian과의 이별 소식
I have to spread it today
오늘은 퍼뜨려야지
Why suddenly?
왜 갑자기?
suddenly?
갑자기?
Are you having a hard time waiting even a few days these days?
요즘 며칠도 기다리기 힘드시죠?
I don't know what my uncle is talking about.
삼촌이 무슨 말을 하는지 모르겠어
correct
옳은
Hua Qian told me to bring the message.
Hua Qian이 나에게 메시지를 가져오라고 했어요
what?
무엇?
She said you owe her
그녀는 당신이 그녀에게 빚을 졌다고 말했어요
two lives
두 개의 삶
Ouch
아야오
Earlier you said that I blindly trust Hua Qian.
앞서 당신은 내가 Hua Qian을 맹목적으로 신뢰한다고 말했습니다.
She took advantage of this to commit numerous tricks.
그녀는 이것을 이용하여 수많은 속임수를 저질렀습니다.
great
좋아요
she used to
그녀는 예전에
What about you?
당신은 어떤가요?
parking
주차
-document -here it is
-문서 -여기 있어요
let's go
갑시다
What's in the bag?
가방 안에는 무엇이 있나요?
It's all clothes
다 옷이네
walk
걷다
Please check carefully
주의 깊게 확인하세요
- Let's go, hold on. - Thank you.
- 가자, 잠깐만 - 고마워요
next
다음
Stop and check it out
멈춰서 확인해보세요
- Stop. - Did you see that?
- 그만해 - 봤어?
I've never seen it before...
한 번도 본 적이 없다 ‥
-Wait a minute, have you seen anyone suspicious? -no
-잠깐만요, 수상한 사람 본 적 있나요? -아니요
Why are there so many officers and soldiers on the streets?
거리에 왜 그렇게 많은 장교와 군인이 있습니까?
owner
소유자
Martial law is now becoming more stringent in this city.
지금 이 도시에는 계엄령이 더욱 엄격해지고 있습니다.
People leaving the city, people behaving badly on the streets.
도시를 떠나는 사람들, 거리에서 나쁜 행동을 하는 사람들
Individual D-Shop customers are being questioned one by one.
디샵의 개별 고객들이 하나씩 심문을 받고 있습니다.
Although the owner changes restaurants every few days,
주인이 며칠에 한 번씩 식당을 바꾸긴 하지만
But as time goes by
하지만 시간이 지날수록
It's inevitable that someone will notice
누군가 알아차리는 건 어쩔 수 없는 일이야
Have you found a way out of the city?
도시에서 나갈 길을 마련하셨나요?
The main entrance is strictly prohibited
정문은 절대 금지되어 있습니다
There is strict security and interrogation.
거기는 엄격한 경비와 심문을 받고 있어요.
The eastern side of the city has Donghuang Mountain in the background.
도시의 동쪽은 동황산(Donghuang Mountain)을 배경으로 하고 있습니다.
The road over there is rough and steep.
저기 길은 험하고 가파르다
A place no one would normally pass by
평소에는 아무도 지나치지 않을 곳
So the guards were so weak that they came and went.
그래서 경비병들이 너무 약해서 왔다 갔다 하더군요
we can give it a try
우리는 한번 시도해 볼 수 있습니다
escape?
탈출?
No, there aren't many of us in the city now.
아니요, 지금 도시에는 우리가 많지 않습니다.
If the owner wants to leave
주인이 나가고 싶어하면
Then other people will create chaos at the front door
그러면 다른 사람들이 정문에서 혼란을 일으킬 것입니다
lead the people
사람들을 이끌어
Then leave unnoticed on the east side of the city.
그 때는 눈에 띄지 않게 도시의 동쪽에서 떠나십시오.
It's not difficult
어렵지 않아요
owner
소유자
The longer you delay, the harder it will be to leave.
지체할수록 떠나기가 더 어려워질 것입니다.
What am I drawing?
나는 무엇을 그리고 있는 걸까?
at last
결국
I lost my wife and I lost my army.
나는 아내를 잃었고 군대도 잃었습니다
But that's my parrot
하지만 그건 내 앵무새야
That person should have been mine too
그 사람도 내 사람이었어야 했는데
It was definitely love at first sight
분명 첫눈에 반한 사랑이었지
I just found something that suits me
방금 나한테 맞는 걸 찾았어
excuse for temptation
유혹에 대한 변명
I should have known sooner
더 일찍 알았어야 했는데
Grab the person and run away
사람을 붙잡고 도망가세요
owner
소유자
are you okay
괜찮아요
Just do what you say.
그냥 당신이 말하는 대로 따르세요.
this car
이 차
Your brother sent me here before.
네 형이 전에 여기로 보냈어
He knows I like cars.
그 사람은 내가 차를 좋아한다는 걸 알아요
I spent a lot of gold and silver
금과 은을 많이 썼어요
I went and bought this fragrant tea.
가서 이 향긋한 차를 사왔어
I scolded him often.
나는 그 사람을 자주 꾸짖었다.
But he still didn't listen
하지만 그는 여전히 귀를 기울이지 않았다
and me
그리고 나
I can't bear to let others taste it either.
나도 남들한테 맛보게 하는 건 참을 수 없어
Give it a try and see what happens
한번 시도해보고 어떻게 되는지 살펴보세요
How is your mother these days?
요즘 어머니는 어떤가요?
Don't cry or make a fuss
울거나 소란을 피우지 않음
much more stable
훨씬 더 안정적
If it's okay, go to that person's room and see them often.
괜찮다면 그 사람 방에 가서 자주 만나세요.
After all, you are now her only child.
결국 당신은 이제 그녀의 유일한 자녀입니다.
She won't bother you when she wakes up.
그녀는 깨어났을 때 당신을 괴롭히지 않을 것입니다.
What's the problem?
무슨 문제 있어?
decent
괜찮은
It must be a legacy of a previous injury.
이전 부상의 유산이어야 합니다.
Try living a little
좀 살아봐
I will give you your brother's memorial tablet.
네 동생의 위패를 네게 주리라
return to hometown shrine
고향의 사당으로 돌아가다
At that time, I will resign from my position as governor.
그 때 저는 도지사직을 사임하겠습니다.
To avoid the clan's old stubbornness
클랜의 오래된 완고함을 피하기 위해
I see that I have lost my will
내가 의지를 잃은 것을 보니
It is inevitable that other thoughts will arise that interfere with it.
그것을 방해하는 다른 생각이 일어나는 것은 불가피합니다.
Everything is according to the will of the Father
모든 것은 아버지의 뜻에 따릅니다
Qian Er
치엔얼
Is there a place in particular that Qian’er wants to go?
Qian'er가 특별히 가고 싶은 곳이 있나요?
What about after this problem is over?
이 문제가 끝난 후에는 어떻습니까?
Let’s not rush and go back to our hometown.
서두르지 말고 고향으로 돌아가자.
Take a little trip around
주변을 좀 여행해 보세요
By the way, please take care of your mom and rest in peace.
그나저나, 엄마를 모시고 편히 쉬세요
Think of it this way
이렇게 생각해보세요
After spending many years in Hwangcheong
황청에서 오랜 세월을 보낸 후
I never took you out alone
난 널 혼자 데리고 나온 적 없어
It's actually because I've neglected you too much.
그건 사실 내가 당신을 너무 소홀히 했기 때문이에요.
Dad, can you help me?
아버지, 저 좀 도와주실 수 있나요?
Did you run into a problem?
문제가 발생했나요?
My security guard was hurt.
내 경비원이 다쳤어요
I want to check something
뭔가 확인하고 싶어
But there is no one around who can use it.
하지만 그것을 사용할 수 있는 사람은 주변에 없다.
tell me something
나한테 뭔가 말해봐
I'll help you solve it
해결 도와드릴게요
It's no big deal
별거 아니야
I can do it myself
내 스스로 할 수있어
Qian Er
치엔얼
You can call the people in this house whatever you want.
이 집에 있는 사람들을 마음대로 불러도 돼요
you don't have to tell me
나한테 말할 필요는 없어
When there is a special problem that cannot be resolved
해결할 수 없는 특별한 일이 있는 경우
Please say again
다시 말해주세요
thank you father
아버지 감사합니다
Why are you being more polite to me?
왜 나한테는 더 예의바르게 대하는 거야?
Drink it quickly
빨리 마셔
Second daughter...
둘째딸 ‥
People have already chosen
사람들은 이미 선택했어요
these guys are pretty good
이 사람들 꽤 괜찮아요
After all, people are smart
역시 사람은 똑똑하다
There are too few people
사람이 너무 적어요
I'll pick a few more later.
나중에 몇 개 더 골라보겠습니다.
good
좋은
You don't need to show him again.
그 사람을 다시 보여줄 필요는 없습니다.
Then you just follow what I say.
그럼 넌 내 말만 따라해
Just organize it.
그냥 정리하세요
But according to the second girl's command,
하지만 둘째 소녀의 명령에 따라
you six
너희 여섯 명
I will go and guard the area around Zhongyi in a moment.
잠시 후에 내가 가서 종자이 주변 지역을 경비하겠습니다.
There are two main points:
두 가지 주요 사항이 있습니다.
one
하나
Special attention needs to be paid to
에 특별한 주의를 기울일 필요가 있다
Mu Xiaoniang’s every move
Mu Xiaoniang의 모든 움직임
When she leaves, you follow.
그녀가 나가면 당신도 따라오죠
don't warn the snake
뱀에게 경고하지 마세요
Tell me who she met when she came back
그녀가 돌아왔을 때 누구를 만났는지 말해주세요
Second, I want to check if anyone visits the servant's house at night.
둘째, 밤에 종의 집을 방문하는 사람이 있는지 확인하고 싶습니다.
Then find out the whereabouts of this person.
그렇다면 이 사람의 행방을 알아내라
Just come back and report it
그냥 돌아와서 신고하세요
Yes, the second girl.
응, 둘째 여자야
I don't care if I get found
발견되도 상관없어
Just tell me you are Hwa-sai's guard.
그냥 당신이 화자이의 경비병이라고 말해주세요
Follow my orders and monitor Mu Yao from here.
내 명령에 따라 여기에서 Mu Yao를 모니터링하십시오.
No matter what other people say
다른 사람들이 뭐라고 해도
subordinates know
부하들은 알고 있다
go down
내려가다
yes
예
second girl
두 번째 소녀
Even if those people are good at it
그 사람들이 잘한다고 해도
I'm worried that I won't be able to fully monitor Zhongzhai.
Zhongzhai를 완전히 모니터링할 수 없을 것 같아 걱정됩니다.
After all, there are many capable people in Zhongzhai.
결국 중자이에는 유능한 사람들이 많이 있습니다.
i know
알아요
So I just left it alone.
그래서 난 그냥 놔뒀어
Just look at Muyao
그냥 무야오만 쳐다봐
You will find 6 more people later.
나중에 6명을 더 찾을 수 있습니다.
Please take turns working with 6 people right now.
지금 당장 6명씩 번갈아가며 근무하세요
Remember, don't relax at all
기억해 조금이라도 긴장을 풀지 마세요
Hwangcheong is currently under martial law.
황청은 현재 계엄령을 받고 있다.
There's no escape for a while
한동안 도망갈 길이 없어
Moreover, depending on the personality
게다가 성격에 따라
It's impossible to just leave without saying goodbye.
인사도 없이 그냥 떠나는 건 불가능해요.
So, you have to keep an eye on Mu Yao.
그러니까 무야오의 옆을 잘 지켜봐야 해
not a last resort
최후의 수단이 아닌
don't fight her
그녀와 맞서지 마세요
I don't want to deal with Mu Yao yet.
아직은 무야오를 상대하고 싶지 않아요
playing the piano to a cow
소에게 피아노 연주하기
Second daughter, don't worry
둘째 딸, 걱정하지 마세요
I will definitely tell them again and again.
나는 그들에게 반드시 몇 번이고 말할 것이다.
just do your best
그냥 최선을 다해
After all, if a monk can escape, he cannot escape from the temple.
결국 스님이 탈출할 수 있다면 절에서 탈출할 수는 없습니다.
yes
예
time doesn't wait
시간은 기다려주지 않는다
I can't do this and I can't wait any longer.
나는 이것을 할 수 없고 더 이상 기다릴 수 없습니다.
You go to the servant's garden and hand him a congratulatory card.
당신은 종의 정원에 가서 축하 카드를 건네줍니다.
Just tell the eldest princess I will thank her tomorrow.
그냥 내일 큰공주님께 감사 인사를 드리겠다고 전해 주세요
yes
예
bank
은행
You always take good care of my jewelry.
넌 항상 내 보석을 잘 챙겨주잖아
Once upon a time when the big princess married me,
예전에 큰 공주님이 나와 ​​결혼했을 때,
Do you still remember the white jade bracelet I gave you?
내가 준 백옥팔찌 아직도 기억하니?
slaves remember
노예는 기억한다
Then help me find it.
그럼 내가 찾는 걸 도와줘
I am going to the bell garden tomorrow
나는 내일 종의 정원에 갈 예정이다
Some things must be returned
어떤 것들은 반환되어야 합니다
Yes, it's a girl
응 여자야
uncle
삼촌
I just came back from outside
방금 밖에서 돌아왔어
I discovered secret people around me
내 주변에 은밀한 사람들을 발견했어요
I secretly observed
몰래 관찰했어요
They seemed to be looking at Zhong Zhai.
그들은 Zhong Zhai를 쳐다보고 있는 것 같았습니다.
Whose person is this?
누구의 사람입니까?
It seem to be like that
그런 것 같다
fahrenheit family people
화씨 가문 사람들
Change your clothes and go do something
옷 갈아입고 뭐라도 하러 가
yes
예
Princess, the big girl is here
공주님, 큰 아가씨가 여기 있어요
I met a big princess
큰 공주를 만났어요
come and sit
와서 앉으세요
yes
예
Don't meet for a few days.
며칠 동안 만나지 마세요.
You look much slimmer
훨씬 날씬해보이네요
I haven't been able to leave the house these days.
요즘 집밖을 못나갔는데
Where is the weight loss?
체중 감량은 어디에 있습니까?
big princess
큰 공주
In fact, this time, apart from saying thank you,
사실 이번에는 감사하다는 말과 별개로
I have come to return this bracelet to you.
나는 이 팔찌를 당신에게 돌려주러 왔습니다.
In the end I let you down
결국 나는 당신을 실망시켰어요
What I have given you is yours.
내가 당신에게 준 것은 당신의 것입니다.
You don't have to come back to me again
다시는 내게 돌아오지 않아도 돼
This was passed down by the late emperor to his eldest daughter.
이것은 선황제가 장녀에게 물려준 것입니다.
As an outsider, I cannot and should not dare to accept him.
나는 외부인으로서 감히 그를 받아들일 수 없고, 그를 받아들여서도 안 됩니다.
What does it mean to be an outsider but not an outsider?
아웃사이더이지만 아웃사이더가 아니라는 것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
Even if there is no fate with Laner
랜어와 운명이 없더라도
You don't have to see me outside
밖에서 나를 볼 필요는 없어
Just think of it as a reward from your senior.
그냥 선배한테 받은 보상으로 여기세요.
Thank you so much, princess.
정말 고마워요, 공주님.
since you got married
당신이 결혼한 이후로
I watch all your performances
나는 당신의 모든 공연을 본다
You are a wise child who knows how to advance and retreat.
당신은 전진하고 후퇴할 줄 아는 현명한 아이입니다.
Lander doesn't have much luck.
랜어는 운이 별로 없네
I just got here
방금 여기까지 왔네요
I'm not that stupid girl
나 그렇게 멍청한 여자 아니야
I only know how to show grace to my children.
나는 내 자식에게 은혜 베푸는 법만 알고 있다
From now on you can't go away from me
앞으로는 나에게서 멀어지면 안 돼
If you want to come to the Bell Garden
종의 정원에 오고 싶다면
just come and meet me
그냥 와서 나를 만나요
save me from loneliness
외로움을 구해줘
Are your parents okay?
부모님은 괜찮으세요?
a few days ago
며칠 전
That bogey family is so arrogant
그 보기 가족은 너무 오만해요
public assassination
공개 암살
Don't take our Zhong family seriously at all.
우리 Zhong 가족을 전혀 심각하게 받아들이지 마십시오.
We were the ones who got your brother in trouble after all.
결국 네 형을 곤경에 빠뜨린 건 우리였어
Chief these days
요즘 족장
In pursuit of this problem, I had trouble sleeping and eating.
이 문제를 추구하기 위해 나는 잠을 자고 먹는 데 어려움을 겪었습니다.
I seem to have lost a lot of weight
살이 많이 빠진 것 같다
It's my brother's fate
내 동생의 운명이야
meet a sister like me
나 같은 언니를 만나다
speaking
말하기
I almost missed it two days ago
이틀전에 거의 놓쳤는데
I made the decision for you and forgot to leave.
당신을 위해 결정을 내리고 떠나는 것을 잊었습니다.
Then I thought about it
그러다가 생각해보니
I heard the head of the household gave orders.
가장이 명령을 내렸다고 들었어
Princess, thank you for thinking of me.
공주님, 저를 생각해 주셔서 감사합니다
I can't wait any longer
더 이상 기다릴 수 없어
So I sent someone to deliver the letter to the Central Committee.
그래서 나는 중시원에게 편지를 전달하기 위해 사람을 보냈습니다.
The head of the household just remembered and gave the command.
가장이 방금 기억하고 명령을 내렸습니다.
Chief these days
요즘 족장
to track down the assassin
암살자를 추적하기 위해
I'm so busy that I can't even come to the backyard often.
너무 바빠서 뒷마당에도 자주 오지 못해요.
I don't get to see him often either.
나도 그 사람을 자주 볼 수는 없지
I remembered it the other day and sent someone to bring food.
엊그제 생각이 나서 사람을 보내서 음식을 가져왔습니다.
The result was all in vain
결과는 다 헛수고였어
He was always a steady person.
그 사람은 언제나 꾸준한 사람이었어.
I don't know why
이유를 모르겠어요
I don't know if you know me
당신이 나를 아는지 모르겠어요
Then he quietly slipped out of the servant's garden.
그런 다음 그는 조용히 종의 정원에서 빠져나왔습니다.
If it had been the day before yesterday, the head of the household would have gone to see me.
그저께였다면 가장이 나를 만나러 갔을 것이다.
Our family sympathizes with you on the recent loss of your brother.
우리 가족은 최근 동생을 잃은 것에 대해 공감하고 있습니다.
I miss my dad again
아버지가 또 그리워요
Despite years of service to the Zhong family,
Zhong 가족에 대한 수년간의 봉사에도 불구하고
See for yourself
직접 가보세요
He sent me a certificate of reconciliation.
그는 나에게 화해 증명서를 보냈습니다.
What happened to the owner this time?
이번엔 주인에게 무슨 일이 있었던 걸까요?
so inappropriate
너무 부적절함
Don't take it to heart
마음에 담아두지 마세요
From now on, I will never again allow that person to disturb your peace.
이제부터 다시는 그 사람이 너희의 평안을 어지럽히도록 두지 아니하리라
big princess
큰 공주
Wait until the truth about Mr. Jong's garden party assassination is revealed.
종씨 가든파티 암살의 진실이 밝혀질 때까지 기다리세요
The father will resign himself and return home
아버지는 스스로 사임하고 집으로 돌아갈 것입니다
Then I'll go with that person.
그럼 그 사람이랑 같이 갈게
I am afraid that I will never return to the Imperial City again in this life.
나는 이생에서 다시는 황성으로 돌아오지 못할까 두렵습니다.
why?
왜?
This Hwangcheong is where my brother grew up.
이 황청은 내 동생이 자란 곳이야
It doesn't matter to me
나한테는 상관없어
Or to your parents
아니면 부모님한테
It's not easy to stay for long.
오랫동안 머무르는 것이 쉽지 않습니다.
great
좋아요
This can be happen
그럴 수 있지
don't blame me
나를 비난하지 마세요
The family has always cherished faces.
가족은 항상 얼굴을 소중히 여겼습니다.
Siu and Raynor have been siblings since childhood.
시우와 레이너는 어릴 때부터 남매였다.
If there is a scandal between brothers
형제끼리 싸우는 스캔들이 있는 경우
I'm afraid I won't be able to protect you either.
나도 당신을 지켜주지 못할까 두렵습니다.
Thanks for reminding me, princess.
생각나게 해줘서 고마워요 공주님
Mom, I want to play too
엄마, 나도 놀고 싶어요
Wait a minute , mom, can I put it up a bit more?
잠깐만 요 엄마, 좀 더 올려도 될까요?
I want to let myself go
나 자신을 놓아버리고 싶어
Would you like to solve it yourself?
직접 풀어볼까?
Wait for me to raise it and raise it a little higher
내가 올릴 때까지 기다렸다가 조금 더 높이 올려줘
I want to let myself go
나 자신을 놓아버리고 싶어
then you chase me
그럼 당신은 나를 쫓아
Mom, I'll do it myself.
엄마, 제가 직접 할게요
mother, please give it to me
어머니, 저에게 주세요
myself
내 자신
I'll let you go myself
내가 직접 놔줄게
come
오다
If you like it, hold on tight
맘에 들면 꽉 잡아
great?
좋아요?
Come on, play with me
자, 나랑 놀자
If you like it, hold on tight
맘에 들면 꽉 잡아
What are you dreaming about?
당신은 무엇을 꿈꾸고 있습니까?
I hold on too tightly and won't let go
너무 꽉 붙잡고 놓지 않아
continued
계속되는
Thanks for watching
시청 해주셔서 감사합니다